

ABOUT ME

To give you a bit of background, I'm originally from San Francisco but previously moved to the UK to do my Masters in Data Science, moved to Germany to work as a Data Scientist, and am now doing my PhD here in Cancer Research at the DKFZ. As much as I love what I do, I also love to travel to learn first-hand about different cultures, love music, and love sports.

"SO... WHY APPLY TO CODEOP?"

I want to do my part in giving women+, who are a heavily under-represented part of the tech world, a safe space to learn about topics that I really care about. By having experience in academia and industry, I know first-hand how maledominant the tech community is and I want to help change that by empowering women+ and teaching them the skills they need to succeed.

KEY WORDS

Python Statistics Academia Linux Teaching Consultancy R Machine Learning Start-Up

CONTACT

PHONE: +44 7376 148827

EMAIL: nicholas.a.abad@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nicholasabad/

https://nicholas-abad.github.io/



NICHOLAS ABAD

Bioinformatics / Machine Learning PhD Student at the German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ)

WORK EXPERIENCE

PhD Student at the German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ) (academia) December 2020 – Present / Heidelberg, Germany

- Creating an easy-to-use and scalable bioinformatics/ML pipeline to characterize potentially-cancerous mutations within DNA
- Teach and plan multiple courses/seminars, such as Introduction to Python and ML in Bioinformatics, to university students
- Stay up-to-date in the newest trends in Machine Learning as well as learning about the inner workings of cancer biology, which is a completely new topic to me prior to my PhD

Machine Learning Engineer at Alexander Thamm GmbH (consultancy)
January 2020 – December 2020 / Cologne, Germany

- Worked with customers to create and implement any/all parts of the data science process (i.e. data collection, pre-processing, analysis)
- Created from scratch our company's first ever product, which was a sales forecasting application, that implemented algorithms such as Prophet (Bayesian forecasting method), CNNs and RNNs
- Generated data science and data engineering teaching material (i.e. basics of data science, (un)supervised methods, etc.) that my colleagues used to teach in-house and to our customers

Data Scientist / Machine Learning Engineer at fedger.io (start-up)

November 2018 - December 2019 / Cologne, Germany

- Build and improve upon our object detection deep learning architecture, through the use of Keras and Tensorflow, that was used within the hospitality industry
- Conduct code reviews of other data scientists and software engineers using style guides such as Flake8, PyDocstyle, and PEP8
- Query our database using SQL to get relevant data

EDUCATION

Lancaster University (Lancaster, Lancashire, United Kingdom)

October 2017 – September 2018

Graduated with the highest honors

Courses include Bayesian Inference, Likelihood Inference, Distributed AI, GLMs, Applied Data Mining, and Data Science Ethics

University of San Francisco (San Francisco, California, USA)

August 2012 - May 2016

Courses include Data Mining, Statistics, Mathematical Modeling, Linear Algebra, Combinators, Python Programming, and R Programming

TECHNICAL SKILLS

